Now, let's work through a note completion exercise
from the IELTS Listening Section 4.
The topic of this exercise is Indigenous Art.
Let's analyze how to do this exercise step
by step together.
In step 1, you have to read the
requirement to identify the word limit.
In this exercise, you are only allowed to
write a maximum of two words and a
number.
And the shortest answer will be one word
or a number.
In step 2, you have to read the
title to understand the topic of the recording
and know how many parts the lecture has.
From the title, you can see that the
recording is about Indigenous Australian Art.
The lecture has two main parts, Ancient Art
and Modern Art.
In Ancient Art, there are two parts, Cave
Paintings and Ochre Pigment Usage.
In step 3, you have to read the
questions and underline the keywords.
And then in step 4, you have to
predict what type of information is missing from
each blank and predict distractors.
For example, in blank 1, you need to
fill in a type of ancient art and you
have to write a noun for this
blank.
Now it's your turn to apply these steps before
listening to the audio and completing the exercise.
Excellent!
Now that you've completed the first four steps,
you're ready for step 5.
Listen and fill in the answers.